{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The viscosity of liquid was classified as both dilatant and rheopectic, which means that the viscosity", "opta": "increased with stirring speed but decreased with mixing time", "optb": "increased with stirring speed and increased with mixing time", "optc": "decreased with stirring speed but increased with mixing time", "optd": "decreased with stirring speed and decreased with mixing time", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the detrimental effect of bubbles on animal cells?", "opta": "Cells trapped on the surface of bubbles can be damaged when the bubbles explode, releasing their pressure and surface energies", "optb": "Cells trapped in the moving foam can be dragged apart by the bubbles", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Bubbles can explode in the liquid medium causing the release of ultraviolet radiation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fluid in which the viscosity decreases with increasing stirrer speed and mixing time, can be represented as", "opta": "newtonian fluid", "optb": "pseudoplastic, thixotropic fluid", "optc": "dilatant, rheopectic fluid", "optd": "dilatant, pseudoplastic fluid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Filamentous fungal cells are more shear sensitive than bacterial cells because of", "opta": "the presence of citin in cell walls of filamentous fungi", "optb": "larger in size than bacterial cells and therefore are more susceptible to shear forces", "optc": "fungal cells are much larger than bacterial cells", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscosity of water at STP is approximately", "opta": "0.005 kg.m-1.s-1", "optb": "0.001 kg.m-1.s-1", "optc": "0.003 kg.m-2.s-1", "optd": "0.1 g.cm-1.s-1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bubble free aeration systems requires", "opta": "silicone tubing or gas permeable membranes to facilitate gas transfer", "optb": "carbon dioxide instead of air to supply oxygen", "optc": "silicone tubing or gas permeable membranes to remove carbon dioxide by oxygen in the form of hydrogen peroxide", "optd": "filled headspace of the reactor with carbon dioxide", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Non-linear relationship between shear stress and shear rate exists in", "opta": "newtonian fluids", "optb": "non-newtonian fluids", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the viscosity of a fluid decreases with increasing stirrer speed, then the nature of the fluid is", "opta": "newtonian", "optb": "pseudoplastic", "optc": "dilatant", "optd": "thixotropic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pseudoplastic fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with increasing stirrer speed", "optd": "decreases with increasing stirrer speed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A viscoelastic fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with increasing stirrer speed", "optd": "decreases with increasing stirrer speed", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mixing in stirred tank reactors can", "opta": "be described as either laminar, transient or turbulent", "optb": "achieve turbulent conditions by increasing the stirrer speed", "optc": "induce laminar flow conditions by the addition of baffles", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In animal cell bioreactor, bubble damage can be minimized by", "opta": "the addition of a shear protectorant", "optb": "using a bubble free oxygen delivery system", "optc": "headspace aeration", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscosity of a fluid changes with either stirrer speed or mixing time. But when mixing ceases, the viscosity returns to its original state. This fluid is best described as", "opta": "newtonian", "optb": "rheopectic", "optc": "viscoelastic", "optd": "thixotropic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sparged mammalian cell bioreactors, the cell damage is caused because of", "opta": "shear stress arising during mixing of the cell culture fluid", "optb": "shear stresses arising from the breakup of bubbles at the liquid surface", "optc": "shear stresses between bubbles in foam at the liquid surface", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SI unit for viscosity is", "opta": "kg.m-1.s-1", "optb": "kg.m-2.s-2", "optc": "kg.m-3.s-1", "optd": "kg.m-1.s-2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscous nature of a non-Newtonian fluid", "opta": "remains constant with time and power input", "optb": "changes with the level of power input and/or the length of time during which the fluid is mixed", "optc": "is similar to that of a perfect gas", "optd": "is similar to that of water", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following compound, if added to a solution will lead to the greatest increase in viscosity?", "opta": "A globular protein", "optb": "Glucose", "optc": "A long chain protein such as albumin", "optd": "Water", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Brookfield viscometer measures viscosity by determining", "opta": "the shear stress", "optb": "the shear rate", "optc": "the shear stress and shear rate", "optd": "the torque required to move an impeller at a set speed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following factors will affect the sensitivity of animal cells to shear conditions?", "opta": "Cell size", "optb": "Availability of nutrients in the medium", "optc": "The presence of shear protectorants in the medium", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The best described action of Pluronic F68 (non-ionic detergent) in a cell culture medium is that, it", "opta": "acts on the surface properties of the cells and the culture medium", "optb": "provides nutrients for the cells", "optc": "acts as a flocculant", "optd": "acts as a coagulant", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water is a", "opta": "newtonian fluid", "optb": "pseudoplastic", "optc": "dilatant", "optd": "rheopectic", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following affect the Kolmogorov eddy size?", "opta": "Stirrer speed", "optb": "Physical properties of the liquid", "optc": "Size and type of impeller", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A liquid is flowing at 11,400 l.h-1 along a pipeline having a diameter of 4 cm. If the liquid has a density of 1 g.ml-1 and viscosity of 0.001kg.m-1.s-1, then the liquid would be in the", "opta": "laminar phase", "optb": "transient phase", "optc": "turbulent phase", "optd": "any of the phase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscosity of a fluid increases with the length of time that it is being mixed. This fluid would be best described as being", "opta": "newtonian", "optb": "rheopectic", "optc": "viscoelastic", "optd": "thixotropic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can act as a shear protectorant?", "opta": "Serum", "optb": "Silicone oil", "optc": "Glucose", "optd": "Glutamic acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscosity of a fluid increases with increasing stirrer speed. This fluid would be best described as being", "opta": "newtonian", "optb": "pseudoplastic", "optc": "dilatant", "optd": "thixotropic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A dilatant fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with increasing stirrer speed", "optd": "decreases with increasing stirrer speed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rheopectic fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with mixing time", "optd": "decreases with mixing time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fluid in which the viscosity increases with increasing stirrer speed and mixing time can be called as", "opta": "newtonian fluid", "optb": "pseudoplastic, thixotropic fluid", "optc": "dilatant, rheopectic fluid", "optd": "dilatant pseudoplastic fluid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The medium will have the highest viscosity (considering that the cells do not secrete gums) with the presence of", "opta": "single celled bacteria", "optb": "filamentous fungi that form pellets", "optc": "filamentous fungi that grow as long poorly branched chains", "optd": "yeast", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Newtonian fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with increasing stirrer speed", "optd": "decreases with increasing stirrer speed", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which pattern of mixing is preferred in stirred tank reactors during the culture of aerobic microorganisms?", "opta": "Laminar flow", "optb": "Transient flow", "optc": "turbulent flow", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Animal cell cultures do not have much effect on shear forces because", "opta": "the cell size is generally smaller than the critical eddy size at which shear will have an effect", "optb": "cells are larger than the critical eddy size at which shear will have an effect", "optc": "animal cells have cell walls", "optd": "animal cells have cell membranes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viscosity of the culture fluid is classified as both pseudoplastic and thixotropic which indicates that the viscosity", "opta": "increases with stirring speed but decreases with mixing time", "optb": "increases with stirring speed and increases with mixing time", "optc": "decreases with stirring speed but increases with mixing time", "optd": "decreases with stirring speed and decreases with mixing time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pluronic F68 is added to cell culture media as", "opta": "a nutrient", "optb": "a shear protectorant", "optc": "to increase oxygen transfer rates", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A stirred tank reactor containing a fluid with a density of 2.5 g.ml-1 and viscosity of 0.002 kg m-1s-1 is mixed at 120 rpm. If the fluid is mixed with an impeller having diameter 50 cm, then the Reynolds number of the liquid in the reactor is", "opta": "2500", "optb": "100", "optc": "12,50,000", "optd": "1,000,000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the viscosity of a fluid decreases with the length of time that it is being mixed, then this fluid is", "opta": "newtonian", "optb": "rheopectic", "optc": "viscoelastic", "optd": "thixotropic", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the importance of the Kolmogorov eddy size in the biotechnology?", "opta": "The Kolmogorov eddy size is a measure of the smallest eddy size in a liquid", "optb": "When the Kolmogorov eddy size become equivalent or smaller than the cell or particle diameter, then the cell or particle will become susceptible to shear damage", "optc": "At the Kolmogorov eddy size, much of the energy of the originating eddy will be released", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A thixotropic fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "is constant regardless of the stirrer speed or mixing time", "optb": "changes during mixing but returns to its original state after mixing", "optc": "increases with mixing time", "optd": "decreases with mixing time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Newtonian fluid is one in which the viscosity", "opta": "remains constant with time and power input", "optb": "increases with the level of power input", "optc": "decreases with the level of power input", "optd": "drastically increases with the level of power input", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reynolds number for laminar flow over a plate should be less than", "opta": "500 mm", "optb": "5 x 10-5", "optc": "5 x 105", "optd": "5 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The approach which is commonly used to determine the level of damage to animal cells in a culture medium is to monitor", "opta": "the concentration of lactate in the medium", "optb": "the level of lactate oxidase activity in the medium", "optc": "the level of lactate dehydrogenase activity", "optd": "the level of lactase activity in the medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Brookfield viscometer cannot determine the shear stress because", "opta": "the shear stress is not defined", "optb": "a computer is required", "optc": "the impeller type is given only by numbers", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "The viscosity of liquids and gases decrease with increasing temperature", "optb": "The viscosity of liquids and gases increase with increasing temperature", "optc": "the viscosity of gases increases with increasing temperature, but decreases in liquids", "optd": "the viscosity of gases decreases with increasing temperature, but decreases in liquids.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Komologorov eddy size", "opta": "is constant at all stirrer speeds", "optb": "increases with stirrer speed", "optc": "decreases with stirrer speed", "optd": "becomes zero when the stirrer speed is very low", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pluronic F68 protects mammalian cells from damage stems as it is a/an", "opta": "surface active agent which stabilizes foams", "optb": "surface active agent which destabilizes foams", "optc": "excellent source of vitamins", "optd": "coagulant", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reynolds number for turbulent flow over a plate should be more than", "opta": "5 x 10-5", "optb": "106", "optc": "5 x 105", "optd": "500", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}